Welcome, one and all!
皆さん ようこそ！
The concluding session of our
“Pursue Peace”! Convention is about to begin.
「平和をつくる」地区大会
3日目午後の部です
As you watch the music-video presentation,
これから ミュージックビデオを
ご覧ください
reflect on how learning about our Creator
創造者エホバについて学び
人々に伝えることは
and speaking about him to others
can help us endure any test of faith
喜びや平和を失わずに
信仰の試練を忍耐する助けになります
with joy and peace.
Please enjoy the video.
どうぞお楽しみください
Welcome to the final portion
of this convention,
大会3日目午後の部に
which corresponds to the Sunday
afternoon session on your program.
皆さんを改めて歓迎いたします
The theme scripture
is taken from Romans 15:13,
3日目の主題は
ローマ 15:13から取られています
which says in part:
「希望を与える神が ⋯⋯皆さんを
“May the God who gives hope
fill you with all joy and peace.”
あらゆる喜びと平和で
満たしてくださ［る］」
To begin, let’s sing a song that describes
では 神の王国がもたらす祝福を
描いた歌を歌いましょう
the blessings that God’s Kingdom will bring.
The song is number 23,
23番です 主題は
「エホバは統治を始める」です
entitled “Jehovah Begins His Rule”
—song number 23.
歌は23番です
In Part 1 of our feature Bible drama,
ドラマの第1部では
エホバが昔の人たちに
we saw how Jehovah gave peace
to his servants in the past.
どのように平和を与えたかを
見ることができました
As we near the conclusion
of this system of things,
終わりが近い今 私たちは
エホバが将来に関するご自分の約束を
果たしてくださる という確信を
how can we strengthen our confidence
that Jehovah will fulfill his promises
for the future?
どのように強められるでしょうか
We now invite you to watch Part 2
of the feature Bible drama
では 「エホバは平和へと
導いてくださる」というドラマの
Jehovah Guides Us in the Way of Peace.
第2部をお楽しみください
Bible prophecy is a fascinating subject.
聖書の預言は本当に素晴らしいです
Prophecy is far more than
just predictions about the future.
単に将来のことを前もって
言っているだけではありません
Jehovah knows all the facts.
エホバは全てを知っています
He can even control and change factors
そして 思い描いた通りに
事を導くこともできます
to ensure the outcome he desires.
イザヤ 55:11でこう言っています
At Isaiah 55:11, he says:
“My word that goes out of my mouth . . .
「私の口から出る言葉［は］
成果を収めずに
私のもとに戻ることはない
“will not return to me without results, . . .
必ず私の望むことを成し遂げ［る］」
and it will have sure success.”
Jehovah’s prophecies
エホバの預言は
100パーセント実現してきました
have a perfect record of success.
He has led his people in the past.
その通りになるよう
エホバは導いてきました
So when he prophesies
それで 私たちを平和へと導くという
that he’ll lead his people
to real, lasting peace in the future,
エホバの預言も必ずその通りになります
this isn’t a prediction; it’s a guarantee!
間違いありません 絶対にそうなります
ダニエル書に書かれている
預言を調べると
The prophecies given to Daniel
clearly show that God’s Kingdom
神の王国によって全人類が
平和になるということを確信できます
will without a doubt
bring lasting peace for all mankind.
ユダで捕らえた人の中で
王の夢を解き明かせる者を見つけました
I have found a man from the exiles of Judah
who can make known the interpretation to the king.
I know who he is.
誰かは分かっている
おまえは本当に私が見た夢の内容を話し
解き明かせるのか
Can you really make known to me
the dream that I saw
and its interpretation?
これが あなたが見た夢です
This is your dream.
Jehovah is the Great Timekeeper.
エホバは自分が決めた
タイミングを必ず守ります
The prophetic portions of the book of Daniel
ダニエル書の預言を学ぶと
エホバへの信仰が強まります
build faith by showing that Jehovah knows
the course of history centuries
エホバは将来のことを何百年
いや 何千年も前から知っています
—even millenniums—in advance.
While portions of these prophecies
預言の一部はダニエルの時代に
その通りになりましたが
were fulfilled in Daniel’s time,
大部分はその後 今に至るまでの間に
実現してきています
many of the details are being fulfilled
right down to our day.
この大切な預言の意味を知ると
So as we discover
the significance of these prophecies,
将来に大きな期待が持てます
we’re excited about what lies ahead.
エホバに導かれた人たちのことを
考えると エホバへの信頼は
And our confidence grows as we discern
how Jehovah has been leading
his people all along.
ますます強まります
この王たちの時代に
In the days of those kings,
天の神は決して滅ぼされることのない
王国を建てます
the God of heaven will set up a kingdom
that will never be destroyed.
The divine dream
ダニエルがネブカドネザル王に
解き明かした神からの夢は
that Daniel interprets
for King Nebuchadnezzar
constitutes a prophecy
神が人類をどのように平和にするかを
知る上で とても重要な預言です
crucial for the lasting peace of mankind
—a promise from Jehovah
to set up a Kingdom
その預言によれば エホバは
地球上のどんな国よりも
that would be vastly superior
to earthly kingdoms.
はるかに優れた王国を設立します
歴史を通じて これまで
いろいろなタイプの政府がありましたが
History has shown us
how every type
of human government imaginable has failed.
どれもうまくいきませんでした
So how would Jehovah’s government come?
では どのようにして
王国が建てられるのでしょうか
When would it arrive?
それはいつのことでしょうか
These were questions
Daniel himself likely had.
恐らく ダニエルも
そう疑問に思ったはずです
エホバは秘密を明らかにする神です
Jehovah is “a Revealer of secrets.”
He would eventually answer
時が来れば
疑問に答えてくれるはずです
these questions in due time.
As a diligent student of the Scriptures,
ダニエルは聖書を学ぶことを
習慣にしていたので
the prophet Daniel
エホバは予定したことを必ず実行する
ということを確信していました
had full faith and confidence
in Jehovah’s ability
to schedule events and bring them about.
そして 恐らく
90代になってからのことです
And now likely in his 90’s,
Daniel was particularly interested
ダニエルは 愛する都市エルサレムの
復興についての預言に関心を持ちます
in prophecies regarding the restoration
of his beloved city, Jerusalem.
「バビロンで70年が満了したら
“When 70 years at Babylon are fulfilled,
私はあなたたちに注意を向ける
“I will turn my attention to you,
“and I will make good my promise
私の約束を果たし
あなたたちをこの場所に連れ戻す」
by bringing you back to this place.”
エレミヤの預言を読んで
希望を持てたはずです
Jeremiah’s prophecy
had given Daniel hope
ユダヤ人が間もなく故郷のユダに戻って
because it indicated that the Jews
would soon return to their homeland of Judah
エルサレムと神殿を建て直す
ということが分かったからです
and rebuild Jerusalem along with its temple.
ダニエルが神殿の再建に
関心を持ったのは 自然なことでした
That makes sense
that Daniel would be interested
in the restoration of the temple
because from the time of King Solomon,
ソロモン王の時代から
エルサレムの神殿は
the temple in Jerusalem
was the world center for worship of Jehovah.
エホバの崇拝の中心地だったからです
ユダヤ人みんなにとって
とても重要な場所でした
So it was very important to the Jews.
聖書の中で 神殿はしばしば
「エホバの家」と呼ばれています
In the Scriptures,
the temple was often called
“the house of Jehovah.”
ところが 若者だったダニエルが
Now, after Jehovah allowed young Daniel
and the rest of the Israelites
ほかのイスラエル人たちと一緒に
バビロンに連れていかれた後
to be taken captive to Babylon,
エルサレムの都市と神殿は
破壊されてしまいました
the city of Jerusalem
and the temple were destroyed.
So naturally, a God-fearing man like Daniel
それで ダニエルのように
神に心から仕える人は
would be interested
in seeing the temple rebuilt.
神殿が再建されるのを見たいと
思ったはずです
Again, as a man of faith,
信仰のあついダニエルは
再びエホバに祈ります
Daniel supplicates Jehovah.
O Jehovah,
エホバ 聞いてください
do hear,
お許しください
do forgive.
私たちに注意を向けて
O Jehovah, do pay attention and act.
救ってください！
Do not delay,
あなたご自身のために
for your own sake,
行動を遅らせないでください
O my God.
ダニエル
O Daniel,
now I have come to give you
私はあなたに洞察と理解を
与えるために来ました
insight and understanding.
The visit of this angel
やって来た天使がダニエルの祈りに答え
gave Daniel some answers and a hope.
希望を持てるようにしました
エホバは天使を通して
この先どうなるのかを詳しく伝えました
Jehovah’s messenger provided
so many details of promises to come.
ユダヤ人は必ず故国に戻ることができる
と言って 安心させました
Jehovah assured Daniel
that the Jews would be restored
to their homeland.
Their exile in Babylonia was almost over.
バビロンでの捕囚の生活は
もうすぐ終わります
But that wasn’t the end
of the angel’s message.
でも 天使が伝えたのは
それだけではありません
He gave Daniel insight
それよりももっとスケールの大きな事に
ついてダニエルに教えました
into something of far greater significance.
ダニエルは 約束されていたメシアが
いつ現れるかについて聞きました
Daniel was told when God’s people
could expect the arrival
of the foretold Messiah.
The Messiah would be the ruler
who would make it possible
メシアが王になり
人類は神が最初に考えていた通り
for obedient humans
to regain the blessing of perfect life
いつまでも生きられるようになります
病気はなくなり 死ぬこともありません
—free from sickness, free from death.
The Messiah would pave the way
メシアが人類の
平和のための道をつくります
for lasting peace for mankind.
What a strengthening message
それを聞いて ダニエルは
どんなにうれしかったことでしょう
for Daniel to receive!
And he likely had some questions.
きっといろんな疑問が
湧いてきたはずです
The angel told Daniel
that Jerusalem and its temple
天使はダニエルに エルサレムと神殿は
メシアが現れる前に
再建される と言いました
would be rebuilt before the Messiah arrived.
Yet, at the time,
でも その頃 エルサレムと神殿は
廃墟と化していました
Jerusalem and the temple were in shambles.
How would they rebuild it?
いったい誰が どのようにして
建て直すのでしょうか
And who would be responsible for this?
Babylon had been overtaken by Medo-Persia,
バビロンはやがて
メディア・ペルシャに征服されます
pictured by the silver chest and arms
ネブカドネザルが見た像の
銀の胸と腕に相当する国です
of Nebuchadnezzar’s dream image.
Not long after
征服して間もなく
ペルシャのキュロス王は布告を出します
this change in world rulership,
Persian King Cyrus
issued a royal decree.
それはユダヤ人への王直々の命令で
It was a commission from Cyrus himself
エルサレムに戻って神殿を
建て直すようにというものでした
for the Jews to return to Jerusalem
and rebuild the temple.
このキュロスの対応は
King Cyrus’ release of the Jews
was in notable contrast
ユダヤ人を何十年も捕囚にしていた
バビロンとは大きく違うものでした
with the Babylonians’ desire
to keep them captive.
Cyrus even authorized funds
キュロスは自分の財宝を使って
建設費用を賄う とさえ言いました
from the king’s house
to cover construction expenses.
異教の神を崇拝する王が
Why would this pagan ruler
いったいどうして捕囚のユダヤ人を
解放しようと思うのでしょうか
have any interest in, first of all,
letting the captive Jews free and, second,
しかも エルサレムの神殿の再建の
費用を出すと言うのです
financing the rebuilding
of their temple in Jerusalem?
歴代第二 36:22で
エズラはこう書いています
Ezra’s words at 2 Chronicles 36:22 tell us:
“Jehovah stirred the spirit
of King Cyrus of Persia.”
「エホバはキュロス王の心を
奮い立たせ［た］」
エホバは自分が語った通りの
ことが起きるよう
Jehovah can maneuver events
to make sure his word is fulfilled.
事態をコントロールできます
He can use anyone to accomplish his purpose,
そのために 人の心さえ
動かすことができます
and this would include
even a foreign king, like Cyrus.
たとえそれが キュロスのように
異教の国の王であってもです
So with this decree,
the Jews returned to Judah.
この布告により ユダヤ人は
ユダに戻ることになりました
Launching a construction project
建設プロジェクトをスタートさせ
and resettling an entire city
都市全体を復興するのは
大変な仕事です
was a major undertaking.
High Priest Jeshua and Governor Zerubbabel
祭壇の設置と神殿の再建を監督するよう
were appointed to take the lead
大祭司エシュアと
総督ゼルバベルが任命されました
in setting up the altar
and rebuilding the temple.
ところが問題にぶつかります
But this wasn’t without its challenges.
神殿の建設をやめさせようとして
Enemies of Judah sought
to sabotage the building of the temple,
反対者たちが妨害してきました
attempting to disrupt the peace.
最初の妨害は失敗に終わりましたが
Initial attempts
to halt the building progress failed;
反対者たちの働き掛けにより
however, eventually these enemies succeeded
王はやがて神殿建設を禁止する
命令を出します
in having an official ban
placed on the temple-building work.
どうなってしまうのでしょうか
What was the problem here?
約14年に及ぶ反対に意気をくじかれ
It appears the Jews let fear of man
stop the building work
ユダヤ人たちはついに
建設をやめてしまいました
after about 14 years of constant opposition.
神殿建設には
重要なことが関わっていました
Now, there is a bigger picture at play here.
ダニエル書の預言によれば
Remember, Daniel’s prophecy foretold
エルサレムと神殿はメシアが現れる前に
建て直されることになっていました
that Jerusalem and its temple
would be rebuilt before the Messiah arrived.
Yet, with the work halted,
でも 建設は中止され
神殿は未完成のままです
the temple remained unfinished.
このままだとメシアは現れません
What would that mean
for the coming of the Messiah?
Jeshua and Zerubbabel needed guidance.
エシュアとゼルバベルは
助けを必要としていました
This is where Jehovah
steps in to provide encouragement
事を導くため エホバが行動します
まず 預言者ハガイを遣わします
—first through the prophet Haggai.
ハガイはユダヤ人たちに
問題点をはっきり指摘します
Haggai’s clear and powerful message
gets right to the heart of the matter.
反対があっても
神殿の建設を続けるように と
He conveys Jehovah’s direction to get up
エホバの指示を伝えます
and keep building the temple despite opposition.
The Jews had a decision to make here.
ユダヤ人たちはどうするでしょうか
Would they allow opposition
to hinder the work?
反対に屈し 建設を諦めるでしょうか
それとも エホバの言葉に従って
建設を続けるでしょうか
Or would they listen to Jehovah’s words
through Haggai
and keep rebuilding the temple?
事を導くため エホバはさらに
預言者ゼカリヤを遣わすことにし
To guide them further,
Jehovah spoke to the prophet Zechariah
大切なメッセージが込められた
幻を見せます
and gave him visions
to provide the Jews with a message.
Zechariah made it clear to the Jews
ゼカリヤは エホバが
反対者たちの妨害から守ってくれて
that Jehovah would not allow
their opposers to harm them
神殿を再建できるように
してくれることを伝えました
or thwart the temple-rebuilding work.
神殿を再建できるよう
エホバが導いてくれます
It was only with Jehovah’s guidance
that the Jews would succeed.
Energized by Jehovah’s motivating words
through these two prophets,
エホバが遣わした2人の預言者の言葉に
勇気づけられ
ユダヤ人たちは神殿の建設を
再開しました
they courageously resumed construction
of the temple, and it was inaugurated
そして紀元前515年に完成させました
in 515 B.C.E.
Now, it seems that at some point
でも その時のユダヤ人の熱意は
やがて失われ 数十年が経過します
over the following decades,
the Jews lost their initial zeal.
The temple was rebuilt and inaugurated,
神殿は完成しましたが エルサレムの
城壁や門は所々が崩れたままで
but Jerusalem’s walls and gates remained unfinished,
with huge gaps left in them.
修復されていませんでした
これは重大なことでした 周りの国に
いつ攻められてもおかしくありません
That was significant because the city
was surrounded by enemy nations.
Without the protection of these walls,
城壁がないと エルサレムは
無防備のままになってしまいます
Jerusalem seemed vulnerable.
When Nehemiah learned of this,
ネヘミヤはそのことを聞いて
ひどく悲しみます
he was visibly distressed.
What’s going on, Hanani?
エルサレムはどう？
みんな元気？
How are our people?
Not good.
いやぁ～
The conditions are disgraceful.
とても大変なことになっています
The walls of Jerusalem are broken down,
エルサレムの城壁は破壊されたままで
and its gates have been burned with fire.
門も焼かれたままなんだ
神殿は？
What about the temple?
It stands,
あるよ でもきちんとした奉仕は
行われていない
but the services
are nothing but empty rituals.
祭司たちでさえ神の律法を守ってない
Most of the people and the priests
ignore God’s Law.
Nehemiah must have been shocked
エルサレムの状況を聞いて
ネヘミヤは大きなショックを受けました
to hear about the condition of Jerusalem.
At this time, he was serving as cupbearer
その頃 彼はシュシャンで
ペルシャの王の献酌人をしていました
to the Persian King in Shushan.
The journey from Shushan to Jerusalem
シュシャンとエルサレムは
1600キロほど離れています
was about 1,000 miles (1,600 km).
それでも ネヘミヤは
何とかしなければと考えます
Still,
Nehemiah felt compelled to act.
ネヘミヤは 城壁を修復できることを
知って 喜びました
Nehemiah rejoiced at the prospect
of rebuilding the walls.
The Jews at this time
ユダヤ人たちはやはり
反対者たちを恐れていましたが
were still fearful of their opposers,
but Nehemiah was intent on changing that.
ネヘミヤは勇気づけようとしました
ネヘミヤは これはエホバが
望んでいることだと知っていました
He knew that Jehovah was behind the work.
エホバが望んでいるのであれば
And if Jehovah is behind something,
誰がどんなに反対しようとも
妨げることはできません
there’s no amount of opposition
that can thwart his will,
so the wall repairs began.
城壁の修復は始まります
This isn’t to say
もちろん 何の問題もなく
うまくいくわけではありません
that there were not challenges along the way.
Opposers did not give up.
反対者たちは諦めていません
いい考えがあります
I recommend we turn the accusation
ネヘミヤを反逆の罪で
訴えるのはどうでしょう
of sedition against Nehemiah.
それはいい
That’s brilliant!
Yes,
なるほど その手があるな
he will beg for our help.
ネヘミヤを追い込んでやる
These opposers threatened the Jews,
反対者たちはユダヤ人たちをののしり
策略を巡らし
schemed against them,
and even accused Nehemiah of treason.
王に反逆しているとネヘミヤに
言い掛かりをつけることまでします
Nehemiah’s peace and the peace
ネヘミヤと城壁を修復する
ユダヤ人たちは窮地に立たされます
of the Jews supporting the work was threatened.
But despite the attempts of opposers,
それでも彼らは
エホバが導いてくれることを確信して
Nehemiah and the Jews looked to Jehovah
修復工事を続けました
for guidance and kept working.
エホバがこうなると一度宣言したなら
When Jehovah declares his purpose,
there is nothing that can prevent him
その通りになるのを阻むことは
誰にもできません
from carrying it out.
エルサレムの再建と城壁の完成は
So if Jehovah wanted a rebuilt Jerusalem,
エホバが望んでいることなので
complete with rebuilt walls,
ネヘミヤはエホバが修復工事を
Nehemiah would have
complete faith in Jehovah’s ability
必ずサポートしてくれると
確信することができました
to support the rebuilding efforts.
And with this support,
そして そのサポートにより
the city walls were completed
エルサレムの城壁は
わずか52日で完成しました
in just 52 days.
ネヘミヤ ついに完成だ！
Nehemiah, the wall is complete!
That’s it.
よくやったな！
神殿も城壁も完成し
With rebuilt walls and a rebuilt temple,
エルサレムの環境は整いました
physically the city was in good condition.
However, about 12 years later,
しかし 約12年後
ネヘミヤはシュシャンに
戻ることになりました
Nehemiah returned to Shushan.
ネヘミヤがいない間
ユダヤ人は正しい崇拝を
During his prolonged absence,
the spiritual state of the Jews deteriorated.
だんだん行わなくなっていきました
It was so sad,
as many in Israel
fell back into bad practices.
また悪い行いをするように
なってしまいました
Some in the priesthood,
大祭司エルヤシブなどの祭司たちも
不正を行うようになっていました
including High Priest Eliashib,
no longer took their responsibilities seriously.
それで エホバは
堕落した祭司たちを正すために
Therefore, Jehovah raised up the prophet Malachi
預言者マラキを遣わします
to counsel the negligent priests.
なぜレビ族はエホバの名を
軽んじているんだ
Why have you Levites despised Jehovah’s name?
軽んじている？
Despised it?
あなた方は
欠陥のある動物を捧げながら
You present a blind,
lame, or sick animal as a sacrifice
悪いことではないと言っている
and say that it is nothing bad.
エホバは受け入れられるだろうか？
Should Jehovah accept it from your hand?
And there’s another thing you do
それに 神が犠牲を受け入れられない
ほかの理由もあります
so that he no longer
looks favorably on anything you offer.
あなた方は若い時からの妻を
裏切っています
Because you betray the wife of your youth,
although she’s your partner, your legal wife.
The lips of a priest
祭司の唇は知識を保つべきであり
should safeguard knowledge,
民は祭司の口に律法を求めるべきです
and people should seek the law from his mouth.
なのに あなた方は
多くの人の信仰を妨げています
But you,
you have made many stumble.
残念なことに マラキの訴えは
祭司たちに響かなかったようです
Evidently, Malachi’s words
had little effect on the priesthood.
Despite his warnings,
the people refused to change.
どんなに忠告しても
全く変わろうとしませんでした
エルサレムに戻ったネヘミヤは
ひどい状況を見てがくぜんとします
When Nehemiah returned,
what he found shocked him.
For a long time,
長いこと祭司とレビ族は
務めを果たしていません
the priests and the Levites
have not taken their duties seriously.
When the people saw that,
それを見て人々は
10分の1を納めなくなりました
they stopped bringing in tithes.
Without the tithes,
それで祭司たちは
畑仕事に戻ってしまいました
most Levites and singers
returned to their fields.
エルヤシブは食料を持ってくるよう
人々に言わなかったのですか
Did Eliashib
not tell the people to bring your provisions?
あなたが留守の間 マラキが
In your absence,
エルヤシブと祭司たちに
警告を与えました
the prophet Malachi warned him
and all the priests.
But Eliashib—
でも エルヤシブは
食料の置かれていたこの部屋を
He took our storeroom
and emptied it of our provisions.
食堂としてトビヤに使わせています
He gave it to Tobiah to use as a dining hall.
In addition
人々は10分の1を納めないだけでなく
to no longer providing
financial support,
the people started
conducting business on the Sabbath.
安息日に商売を始めることさえします
What are you selling today?
今日は何があるの？
Only the best quality fish from Tyre.
おいしい魚だ ティルスのね
外国人と結婚してもいました
They were marrying foreign women.
今日 ギズラと結婚する
I’m marrying Gizla today.
ギズラ？
Gizla?
That Moabite girl?
モアブ人の？
I heard you bind yourself with an oath
ほかの民族の女性と
結婚しないって誓ったよね？
and a curse not to take a wife from the nations!
このままだとメシアに至る家系に
影響が及び
This action could have disrupted
the line to the Messiah,
and it definitely threatened
to contaminate pure worship.
異教の崇拝が入り込んでくる
恐れがあります
せっかく復興したのに
These men were bringing the restored nation
またエホバに見放されても
おかしくないことをしていたのです
into disfavor with Jehovah.
This is the same reason
why Jehovah allowed Babylon
エルサレムがバビロンに
滅ぼされることになった時と
同じ間違いをしていました
to destroy Jerusalem in the first place.
So Nehemiah took action
against these faithless ones.
それでネヘミヤは
事態を正すために立ち上がります
みんなでこの部屋を清め
全て元に戻しなさい
Please cleanse this room
and replace the utensils.
やめてくれ
No!
おっしゃる通りに
Yes, my lord.
And gather all the Levites,
全てのレビ族と歌い手たち
代官たちを集めなさい
the singers, and the deputy rulers to me.
I’m assigning them all back to their posts.
みんなを持ち場に戻らせます
He enforced the strict observance
安息日をしっかり守るようにと言います
of the Sabbath.
一体どういうつもりだ？
昨日は野宿したんだぞ
What’s the meaning of this?
I had to sleep on the ground last night.
You know God’s Law:
律法を知ってますよね
安息日には仕事も商売もしてはいけない
No work,
no business on the Sabbath!
帰りなさい！安息日を神聖なものと
するために見張ってください
Go!
You and all the Levites, guard the gates
and keep the Sabbath holy.
誰も入れてはいけません
Don’t let anyone in!
He disciplined those
who had taken foreign wives.
外国人と結婚している人たちも正します
あなたは エホバに仕えていない人と
結婚しないと誓いましたね
Did you not swear never to marry someone
who doesn’t serve Jehovah?
ネヘミヤ もう昔の話です
Nehemiah, nobody cares.
何言ってるんだ！
Did you not?
分かった 分かった！
Yes! Yes!
Then why have you ignored the command of Jehovah
なぜ エホバの命令と
自分の誓約を軽んじるのですか
and your own oath?
間違いなく エホバが
ネヘミヤをずっと導いていました
There’s no doubt
that Jehovah
was guiding Nehemiah’s efforts all along.
この大々的な立て直しにより
After a spiritual cleansing was done,
a measure of peace was again enjoyed.
再び平和が戻ってきました
And with this vigorous
背教者たちが一掃された
この記録をもって
rooting out of apostasy,
the record of the Hebrew Scriptures
ヘブライ語聖書の最終章は
終わっています
comes to a close.
そこからイエスの誕生までの
数百年の記録は 聖書に載っていません
Now, we don’t have
an inspired record of events
in the centuries leading up to Jesus’ birth,
でも 歴史によると エルサレムには
その間 いろいろな変化がありました
but history shows that Jerusalem
underwent several changes during these years.
The Medo-Persian Empire
メディア･ペルシャは
ギリシャに征服されます
was overtaken by Greece,
ネブカドネザルが見た像の
銅の腹とももに相当する国です
represented by the copper belly and thighs
of Nebuchadnezzar’s dream image.
ギリシャが治めるようになっても
エルサレムは無事に存続しましたが
While the city seemed to survive
the change in control
without any physical damage,
its spiritual state was threatened.
崇拝の面ではそうはいきませんでした
The Greek Empire set the stage for the spread
ギリシャ帝国の繁栄により
ギリシャの言語 文化
宗教思想が広まっていき
of Greek language, culture, and religious thought,
イスラエルもその影響を受けました
and Israel was affected by this influence.
後に アンティオコス4世は
Years later, King Antiochus IV
ユダヤ人の宗教と習慣を
根絶しようとしました
was determined to eradicate
Jewish worship and customs.
エホバの神殿でギリシャの神ゼウスに
He went so far as to sacrifice a pig
to the Greek god Zeus
豚を犠牲として捧げることまでしました
at the temple of Jehovah.
This was a vicious attempt
これは正しい崇拝を汚す
ひどい行為でした
to defile and to stamp out pure worship.
ところが これにより
思わぬ展開になります
However, the desecration
had the opposite effect.
It sparked an uprising
決起したユダヤ人たちが反乱を起こし
of zealous Jews, and three years later,
神殿を清めて
再びエホバに奉献しました
they cleansed the temple
and rededicated it to Jehovah.
約100年後 ギリシャに代わって
別の大国ローマが登場し
About a century later,
Jerusalem experienced
another change in rulership
as Rome became the dominant world power.
エルサレムもその統治下に入ります
ネブカドネザルが見た像の
鉄のすねに相当する国です
Rome corresponded to the legs of iron
in Nebuchadnezzar’s dream image.
Under the rule
ヘロデ大王の統治の下
エルサレムは非常に繁栄しました
of Herod the Great,
Jerusalem enjoyed considerable prosperity.
ヘロデ大王の一番の功績は
Herod’s greatest work, however,
was the reconstruction of the temple
神殿とそれに付属する建物の再建です
and its building complex.
神殿で犠牲を捧げることは イエスが
生まれる頃にも行われていました
The temple and its daily sacrifices
remained in operation down to Jesus’ day.
The Bible record picks up
聖書の記録はその頃から再び始まります
before Jesus was born.
エホバ 憐れみを！
May Jehovah have mercy on us!
何ごとだ？
What’s happening?
もう朝なの？
Is the sun up already?
Are they . . .
あれは天使かな？
are they . . . angels?
恐れることはありません
Do not be afraid,
for look!
見よ 私は大きな喜びとなる
良い知らせを告げているのです
I am declaring to you good news
of a great joy that all the people will have.
今日 ダビデの都市で
主なるキリストが生まれたからです
For today there was born
to you in David’s city a savior,
who is Christ the Lord.
イエスについての多くの預言が
その通りになりました
Jesus’ birth and ministry
fulfilled many prophecies.
西暦29年 エホバは
イエスに聖なる力を注ぎます
In 29 C.E., Jehovah
anointed Jesus with holy spirit.
This corresponds exactly
to the words of Daniel’s prophecy
これはまさに500年以上も前に
エホバがダニエルに伝えた
預言の通りの事でした
that Jehovah gave him
more than 500 years earlier.
The promised Messiah had arrived!
約束されていたメシアが現れました
Early in his ministry, Jesus read these words
宣教を始めた頃
イエスはイザヤの預言を読み上げます
from the prophecy of Isaiah.
The scroll of Isaiah the prophet reads:
イザヤにはこうあります
「エホバの聖なる力が私の上にある
“Jehovah’s spirit is upon me,
“because he anointed me
神が私を選び
“to declare good news to the poor.
貧しい人に良い知らせを
告げるようにさせたからである
“He sent me
私は神から遣わされて
捕らわれている人に釈放を
“to proclaim liberty to the captives
“and a recovery of sight to the blind,
目が見えない人に視力の回復を知らせ
“to send the crushed ones away free,
to preach Jehovah’s acceptable year.”
エホバに受け入れられる年を伝える」
今日 皆さんが聞いたこの聖句が
Today this scripture
that you just heard is fulfilled.
実現しています
聖なる力を受けて イエスはわずか
数年の間にたくさんの奇跡を行いました
Holy spirit empowered Jesus to perform
many miracles
in just a few short years on earth.
This had a profound effect
on the people living in his day.
多くの人がイエスを
信じるようになりました
I am a very sick woman.
私 実は病気で
I’ve suffered from a flow of blood
12年ほど血の流出に
苦しんでいるんです
for some 12 years.
He can heal me!
イエスなら治せます！
Even if I could touch
あの方の外衣の房べりに
触れることができれば
just the fringes
of his outer garment, I will get well!
良くなるでしょう！
Who touched my outer garment?
誰か触りましたか？
Who touched me?
私の外衣に
Please, . . .
主よ どうか お許しください
please forgive me, my Lord.
触ったのは私です！
It was I who touched you!
信仰を持ったのです！
I have faith in you!
I knew that if I could just touch
あなたに
その外衣の房べりに触れるだけで
私は良くなる と思いました
the fringes of your outer garment,
I could get well.
Take courage, daughter!
娘よ！
Your faith has made you well.
あなたの信仰が良くならせました
これまで見たこともないような
奇跡を見て 人々は驚きました
The miracles Jesus performed were unlike
anything the people had seen before.
Finally, the people had hope
ついに 希望を見つけました
明るい将来がある という希望です
—a hope for the future, a hope for peace.
しかも 世界を良くしようとする
どんな人にもできないことを
He even demonstrated that he had power
far beyond any human ruler.
イエスは行いました
Lord, Mary is here!
連れてきました
主よ もしいてくださったなら
Lord!
If you had been here,
彼は死ななかったでしょう！
my brother would not have died!
ラザロよ 出てきなさい！
Lazarus!
Come out!
さあ 解いてあげなさい！
Free him, and let him go!
イエスが行ったことは私たちに
素晴らしいことを教えてくれます
There is so much we can learn
from Jesus’ miracles, works, and teachings.
エホバがどんな世界を願い
They reveal Jehovah’s purpose and power.
どれほどの力を持っているか
They show how enjoyable,
イエスが治める世界での暮らしが
how peaceful life will be
under God’s Messianic Ruler.
どれほど平和で幸せなものか
イエスの力を見た人たちは
大きな期待を抱きました
Humans alive at this time
could see visible proof of this.
Jesus’ ministry accomplished so much
イエスはわずか3年半の間に
非常に多くのことを行いました
in just three and a half years.
メシアについて預言されていたことが
次々と起き
And prophecy regarding the Messiah
continued to be fulfilled
as his opposers succeeded
イエスは杭に掛けられて
処刑されました
in putting him to death.
With the sacrifice
イエスが命を
犠牲として捧げたことにより
of Jesus’ perfect human life,
the entire arrangement
エホバへの崇拝の仕方が
大きく変わりました
for worshipping Jehovah had changed.
There was no longer a need
for animal sacrifices.
動物の犠牲はもう必要ありません
崇拝のためにエルサレムの神殿に
行く必要も もうありません
Pure worship was no longer centered
around the temple in Jerusalem.
メシアを通して行うのが
エホバへの正しい崇拝です
The only way to worship Jehovah acceptably
was through the Messiah.
イエスの犠牲に信仰を持つなら
Now people everywhere
could find the way to peace
エホバに喜ばれ 誰もが明るい将来を
見つめることができます
through faith in Jesus’ ransom sacrifice.
モーセの律法に基づく
崇拝の取り決めは終わりました
The Jewish system of worship
under the Mosaic Law was over.
Jerusalem and the temple
no longer had Jehovah’s favor.
エルサレムも神殿ももう必要ありません
Jesus’ perfect human sacrifice
いつまでも平和に暮らせる世界を
可能にするのは
was the only solution for lasting peace.
イエスが捧げた犠牲です
So, what did this mean
for the city of Jerusalem and the temple?
それでは エルサレムと神殿は
どうなるのでしょうか
Well, before his death,
イエスは亡くなる前
Jesus provided his followers with a warning
エルサレムが陥落することについて
知らせ 指示を与えました
regarding Jerusalem’s destruction.
ルカ 21:20, 21で
こう言っています
At Luke 21:20, 21, he says:
“When you see Jerusalem
「エルサレムが陣営を張った軍隊に
囲まれるのを見たなら
“surrounded by encamped armies,
その時 荒廃が近づいたことを
知りなさい⋯⋯
“then know that the desolating of her
“has drawn near. . . .
“Let those in the midst of her leave,
都の中にいる人はそこを出なさい
and let those in the countryside
not enter into her.”
田舎にいる人は
都に入ってはなりません」
イエスは素晴らしい指導者です
A good ruler guides his people.
Although it wasn’t yet time for him
to take the throne as Ruler of God’s Kingdom,
神の王国の王になるのは
まだ先のことでしたが
王として優れた素質を持っていることが
Jesus (by the way he acted) gave us insight
into the kind of ruler he would be.
この時のイエスの行動から
よく分かります
By providing first-century Christians
エルサレムとユダヤから逃げるようにと
指示することによって
with a warning to leave Jerusalem
イエスは1世紀のクリスチャンたちを
導き 守りました
and all Judea,
he was guiding them and protecting them.
Jesus prophesied the destruction of the city,
イエスは都市の陥落を預言し
数十年後 預言はその通りになりました
and just a few decades later,
that prophecy came true.
The Roman Empire still had control of Judea,
西暦66年 ユダヤは依然として
ローマ帝国の配下にあり
and tensions ran high
between the Romans and the Jews.
そのことに不満を募らせたユダヤ人が
ついに反乱を起こします
Eventually, the Jews
revolted against Roman rule.
やって来たローマ軍に
エルサレムは完全に包囲され
With the city surrounded
and Roman forces closing in,
逃げようがないと思われました
it seemed there was no way out.
でも エホバの言葉は
必ずその通りになります
But Jehovah’s word cannot go unfulfilled.
イエスが言ったように
逃げるタイミングがやって来ました
For no apparent reason,
the Roman forces withdrew!
どういうわけか
ローマ軍が撤退したのです
For faithful Christians,
その機会を逃さずに イエスに
言われていた通りにした人たちは
this was their opportunity.
It’s simple:
安全な所へ逃げることができました
Those who followed Jesus’ direction
to leave Judea were guided to safety.
For those who delayed,
反対に すぐに行動しなかった人たちは
逃げられなくなりました
escape became difficult or impossible.
There was no doubt
もはや エルサレムはエホバにとって
特別な都市ではありませんでした
that Jerusalem no longer enjoyed
Jehovah’s special favor and protection.
守られることはありません
The city and its temple
都市と神殿は完全に破壊されました
were completely destroyed.
1世紀のクリスチャンが
There are parallels we can draw
from the warning Jesus gave
イエスから前もって
警告を与えられていたのと同じように
to those first-century Christians
私たちも警告を与えられています
to the warning we
have been given for our day.
Jesus gave us one composite sign
世界の体制の終わりが近づいた時に
どんなことが起きるかを
that indicates the destruction
of this current system of things
イエスはあらかじめ教えてくれました
is very close.
聖書の預言によれば
Prophecies in the Bible give us no doubt
今が終わりの時代であることは
間違いありません
that we are living in “the last days.”
エホバは 今後どうなるかについて
細かなことまでは言っていません
Jehovah has not revealed all the details
of how everything will work out.
でも エホバが言ったことは
全て必ずその通りになります
But we know that everything
he has revealed will come true.
This includes details outlining
how world events
エホバは私たちに 人類が
平和になる前の終わりの時代に
would unfold in the time
of the end
世界情勢がどのように変化していくかを
教えてくれています
before mankind
would experience permanent peace.
考えてみてください
ダニエル書の預言によれば
Remember, Daniel’s prophecy indicated
今の体制が終わる頃 1つの政治勢力が
世界で大きな力を持っているはずです
that there would be
only one dominant world power in place
at the time of the end.
By World War I,
第1次世界大戦の頃
the power represented by the feet
鉄と粘土の足に相当する
政治勢力が現れました
of iron and clay had emerged.
During that war, Britain and America
大戦中 イギリスとアメリカは
協力関係を結び
forged a partnership
that continued through the Second World War.
第2次世界大戦の時もそうでした
This means a special relationship
between the British Commonwealth and Empire
and the United States of America.
Neither the sure prevention of war
nor the continuous rise
of world organization will begin
without what I have called
the fraternal association
of the English-speaking people.
英語を話す緊密なこの2つの国は
These two countries
continue to be a dual
English-speaking world power.
世界で大きな力を持ってきました
The characteristics of iron and clay
この政治勢力が鉄と粘土で
表されているのは適切なことです
used to represent
this world power are significant.
足の指には鉄の部分と
粘土の部分があるので
And as the toes of the feet
were partly of iron and partly of clay,
so the kingdom
この王国には強い部分と
もろい部分があることになります
will be partly strong and partly fragile.
At times, the United States and Britain
アメリカとイギリスは戦争に関わり
have displayed ironlike strength
鉄のような強さを見せてきました
through their involvement in armed conflicts.
でも 粘土が混ざっているので
However, iron mixed with clay
is considerably weakened.
もろさがあります
This can be observed as common people
反対意見を持つ一般市民がいるために
undermined the Anglo-American
World Power’s ability
鉄のような強さを
発揮できないことがあります
to act with ironlike strength.
聖書の預言通り
As the political and social developments
世界情勢や社会の動向が
刻々と変化しても
foretold in the Bible come to a climax,
私たちは安心していられます
we have a measure of peace.
We know Jehovah will guide his people,
エホバが私たちを導いてくれます
even as the world’s spiritual
and moral condition sinks to new depths.
世の中がますますおかしくなり
悪くなっていってもです
何も変わっていない
何も問題はない と思って
As many in first-century Jerusalem
continued their lives
生活を続けていた
1世紀の人たちと同じように
as if nothing had changed,
現代の人も今の生活をただ続けています
so, too, today many
continue on with their lives.
でも 私たちは注意を怠りません
Meanwhile, we remain alert
今 世界で起きていることが
預言の通りであることを忘れません
as we see fulfillment of Bible prophecy
right before our eyes.
In the days of those kings,
この王たちの時代に
the God of heaven will set up a kingdom
天の神は決して滅ぼされることのない
王国を建てます
that will never be destroyed.
The book of Revelation
啓示の書から
この先 何が起こるかが分かります
tells us what will soon happen.
The political rulers of the world
will give the United Nations
世界の国々が これまで以上に
国際連合に力を委ねるようになります
unprecedented power and authority.
そして 使徒パウロが言っているように
The apostle Paul foretold
that the nations will declare
国々は「平和だ！安全だ！」と
宣言します
“Peace and security!”
But it won’t prove to be true peace.
でも それは本当の平和ではありません
国連を支持する国々が
The nations supporting the UN
神を正しく崇拝していない宗教を
攻撃します
will attack the institutions
of false religion.
それから エゼキエルが「マゴグの地の
ゴグ」と呼んでいる諸国家の連合体が
Then a coalition of earth’s governments
that the prophet Ezekiel
calls “Gog of the land of Magog”
エホバを崇拝する人たちを攻撃します
will attack God’s people.
Yet, we don’t need to be fearful.
でも 恐れる必要はありません
That’s when we can put into action
その時こそ これまで学んできたことを
生かす時です
all of the lessons we’ve learned.
エホバが導いてくれると信じる人たちは
Those who trust and obey Jehovah’s guidance
恐れることなく
将来を見つめることができます
can look to the near future with confidence.
これまで見てきたように
エホバはいつでも
As we’ve seen, Jehovah has always been
思った通りに事を進めてきました
in control of the situation.
ただ指示を与えるだけで
He has never guided his people
何のサポートもしないということは
決してありませんでした
in a certain direction
but then failed to provide for them.
それで 私たちがこれまで
学んできた人たちについての記録は
That’s why we can say
that the lessons we learn
from the faithful men we’ve studied
ただの感動的な話ではありません
are more than just lessons.
エホバはずっと人類を平和にするために
事を進めてきたのです
This has been Jehovah
paving the way for peace from the start.
振り返ってみると エホバは
大切な人たちをいつでも導いてきました
Looking back, we see exactly
how Jehovah has led his people.
It took many years,
but he’s been in control the whole time.
これまでずっと いつも
エホバが思った通りになってきました
Would it make sense
to think he isn’t in control anymore?
この先はそうならない ということが
あり得るでしょうか
No power in heaven or on earth
エホバが初めに決めたことが
その通りになるのを阻むことは
誰であろうと決してできません
can prevent Jehovah
from accomplishing his express purpose.
He has never relinquished control,
エホバはただ見てきただけ
ではありません
昔も今も事を導いています
and he is still guiding his people.
考えてみてください
Now think about this:
これまでエホバが大切な人たちを
導いてきたのであれば
If Jehovah has guided
his people to this point,
we can have full confidence
たとえ もうどうにもならないと
思えるようなときでも
that trust and obedience to his direction
エホバを信頼し
エホバの言われる通りにすれば
will prove to be our salvation,
必ず助けてくれると
確信できるのではないのでしょうか
even if a way out seems impossible.
Jehovah is all-powerful!
エホバに不可能なことはありません
He’s going to help us
through whatever we may face.
どんなことがあっても
必ず助けてくれます
We won’t have to fight,
戦う必要はありません
恐れなくてよいのです
and we won’t need to fear annihilation.
全てエホバが考えた通りになります
Jehovah has things
under control.
“And this kingdom
その王国はほかのどんな民にも
渡されません
“will not be passed on to any other people.
“It will crush and put an end
これらの王国を全て打ち砕いて終わらせ
“to all these kingdoms.
その王国だけが永遠に存続します
And it alone will stand forever.”
God’s Kingdom will fill
神の王国が世界を治め
and renew the entire earth.
地球全体が楽園になります
Jehovah’s promises
エホバの約束が
完全にその通りになります
will be completely fulfilled.
私たちがずっと願ってきた人類の平和が
ついに実現し もう失われません
Lasting peace will finally become
a reality for all mankind.
イエスの統治によって
Just imagine what faithful servants
世界がどんなふうに新しくなるか
想像してみてください
have to look forward to
under Jesus’ heavenly rule!
これまで誰も見たことがないような
素晴らしい世界になります
He will be able to provide
what no man ever could.
Can you imagine what that will be like?
そこにいる時のことを
思い描いてみてください
“For look!
「私は新しい天と新しい地を
創造している
“I am creating new heavens and a new earth;
“and the former things
will not be called to mind,
以前の事柄は思い出されることも
心に浮かぶこともない」
nor will they come up into the heart.”
“The righteous will possess the earth,
「正しい人は地上に住み続け
そこで永遠に暮らす」
and they will live forever on it.”
“He will swallow up death forever,
「神は死を永久にのみ込む
主権者である主エホバは
全ての顔から涙を拭う」
and the Sovereign Lord Jehovah
will wipe away the tears from all faces.”
「神は人々の目から
全ての涙を拭い去ります
“He will wipe out every tear from their eyes,
“and death will be no more,
もはや死はなくなり
“neither will mourning
悲しみも嘆きも苦痛もなくなります
“nor outcry nor pain be anymore.
以前のものは過ぎ去ったのです」
The former things have passed away.”
“At that time the eyes
「その時 目が見えない人は
見えるようになり
“of the blind will be opened,
耳が聞こえない人は聞こえるようになる
“and the ears of the deaf will be unstopped.
その時 足が不自由な人は
鹿のように跳びはね
“At that time the lame
“will leap like the deer,
“and the tongue of the speechless
口が利けない人は歓声を上げる
“will shout for joy.
荒野に水が湧き出て
“For waters will burst forth
in the wilderness,
砂漠平原に川が流れる」
and streams in the desert plain.”
「人々は家を建てて住み
“They will build houses and live in them,
and they will plant vineyards
and eat their fruitage.”
ブドウ園を造って実を食べる」
「私の民の寿命は木の寿命のようになり
“For the days of my people
will be like the days of a tree,
“and the work of their hands
私が選んだ者たちは
働く喜びを存分に味わう」
my chosen ones will enjoy to the full.”
「温厚な人は地上に住み続け
“But the meek will possess the earth,
“and they will find exquisite delight
豊かな平和をこの上なく喜ぶ」
in the abundance of peace.”
What a faith-strengthening drama!
信仰が強まりました
全てエホバが考えた通りに
なるので安心です
We are at peace knowing that Jehovah
is in complete control.
All in attendance will be pleased to know
that Parts 1 and 2
うれしいことに ドラマ「エホバは
平和へと導いてくださる」
of the drama-documentary
Jehovah Guides Us in the Way of Peace
第1部と第2部は jw.orgと
JW Library®アプリで
are available now for download on jw.org
早速ダウンロードすることができます
Have you enjoyed the original songs
皆さんはこれまで 大会の
オリジナルソングを楽しんできましたか
that have been featured
at recent conventions?
We now have the privilege
of watching a video medley
これから 過去数年の地区大会で歌った
オリジナルソングを聞きながら
and reflecting on the lessons we have learned
大会で学んだことを
思い返してみましょう
at our conventions over the past few years.
お楽しみください
Enjoy!
立ちはだかる恐れの壁
Doubt and fear surround me—
The way ahead not clear.
神が共にいて道を拓く
Through uncertainty you guide me;
I know you’re always near.
敵の軍が押し寄せても
Life may not be easy,
But this I know is true:
わたしの命は神が守る
You’re the God who’s ever loyal;
My life is safe with you.
エホバ すぐそばにいてください
Jehovah, give me eyes of faith
And help me always see
敵より強い軍 見えるように
There are more with us than against us.
Courageous let me be.
今ください 耐えるために
Courage, give me courage;
With courage, I’ll endure.
勇気ください 勝利近い
Jehovah, give me courage;
Your victory is sure.
不意に襲う不安の波
Feeling fear is human.
In my own strength, I’m frail.
自分の力の弱さを知る
You have been my rock and refuge;
Your power never fails.
Help me be courageous,
神に勇気求めるなら
And let my heart be brave.
だれもその勇気取り去れない
Lasting harm can never hold me—
No prison, gate, or grave.
エホバ すぐそばにいてください
Jehovah, give me eyes of faith
And help me always see
敵より強い軍 見えるように
There are more with us than against us.
Courageous let me be.
今ください 耐えるために
Courage, give me courage;
With courage, I’ll endure.
勇気ください 勝利近い
Jehovah, give me courage;
Your victory is sure.
見渡せば あふれる愛
Look around us now;
See the love on each face—
大切な仲間
Out there in the world, hard to find.
あとにした今の世では
All these faithful friends
With the love they all show,
見られない景色
Glad to leave that old world behind.
試みを越え 愛は残る
Love never fails; that’s promised.
It always will endure.
さあ 進もう 神と歩む愛の道を
Love—unfailing love—
That’s what Jehovah gives.
That’s what he is.
今日 確かに 心にある
Love—unfailing love—
That’s what we need to live.
私たちの愛は決して
And the love here today,
In our heart may it stay—
さあ 進もう 神と歩む愛の道を
Love—unfailing love—
That’s what Jehovah gives.
That’s what he is.
今日 確かに 心にある
Love—unfailing love—
That’s what we need to live.
私たちの愛は決して絶えない
And the love here today,
In our heart may it stay—
Unfailing love,
この愛 絶えない
Unfailing love.
炎のように迫る敵たち
Why should I fear the lion?
Why should I fear any foe?
恐れはしない
With Jehovah by my side,
いつもそばにエホバがいるから
I will not run and hide.
My God is with me; this I know.
あなたの助けを信じ
With eyes of faith,
I see beyond the darkness.
あなたから離れない
With eyes of faith,
there’s nothing more to fear.
力もらって強くなろう
With Jehovah, I am strong,
Determined to go on,
進みつづけていこう
Knowing that my God is always near—
あなたと
With eyes of faith.
未来が見える もう目の前に
I see the wondrous future
God has in store for me.
守り抜く この信仰
I need to be strong.
I know it won’t be long
エホバの勝利まで
Till Jehovah claims his victory.
あなたの助けを信じ
With eyes of faith,
I see beyond the darkness.
あなたから離れない
With eyes of faith,
there’s nothing more to fear.
力もらって強くなろう
With Jehovah, I am strong,
Determined to go on,
進みつづけていこう
Knowing that my God is always near—
未来へ
With eyes of faith,
エホバと
With eyes of faith.
星たちまたたく 夜の空
The stars that fill the summer night
Look down from above.
木陰に差し込む 陽の光
The beauty of the day and night
You fashioned with love.
エホバがその手ですべてを造った
Your hands prepared the land and sea,
And ev’rything that came to be
愛込めて
Brought joy to your heart.
あなたの創造 あなたの約束 心が躍る
There is joy in your creation,
In the message of salvation,
And the Paradise to come.
あなたからの愛 永遠にあふれ
But to have your love forever
Is a real and lasting treasure.
この喜びに終わりはない
You alone will prove to be
Our joy eternally.
独り子が命を差し出し
This joy could not be ours
Without the gift of your Son.
永遠の歓喜を実現させた
His sacrifice has paid the price
So joy could be ours for all time.
あなたの創造 あなたの約束 心が躍る
There is joy in your creation,
In the message of salvation,
And the Paradise to come.
あなたからの愛 永遠にあふれ
But to have your love forever
Is a real and lasting treasure.
この喜びに終わりはない
You alone will prove to be
Our joy eternally.
これから歌うのは 将来への確信を
強める賛美の歌です
Our next song encourages us
to look ahead with confidence.
The song is entitled
“See Yourself When All Is New.”
主題は 「新しい世界を見つめて」です
Let’s sing together song number 139.
139番の歌を歌いましょう
歌は139番です
That’s song number 139.